<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>YuLab@SMU</title>
    <link>http://yulab-smu.top/</link>
    <description>Recent content on YuLab@SMU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yulab-smu.top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ggtree入选MEE期刊10周年纪念</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/posts/ggtree-2017-mee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/posts/ggtree-2017-mee/</guid>
      <description>2017年我还在香港大学读博士期间发表了ggtree的第一篇文章，发表在Methods in Ecology and Evolution期刊上，ggtree发表之后，我受邀请去Field Museum做报告，由NIH项目The Open Tree of Life资助，另外在2019年我还受到William Pearson教授的邀请，为Current Protocols in Bioinformatics撰写一文介绍ggtree，可以看出来这项工作还是在业内引起比较大的关注的。
今年2020年是MEE期刊创刊10周年，期刊庆祝10周年的一项活动是在每一卷中找一篇代表作，邀请作者写一写文章背后的故事，而ggtree有幸做为第八卷的代表，我写了一篇文章发表在MEE官方博客上，https://methodsblog.com/2020/11/19/ggtree-tree-visualization/，详细地介绍了开发这一R包的背景，以及后面的发展。
在后面也介绍了我在南方医科大学独立运作一个课题组之后发表的两篇文章：
 LG Wang, TTY Lam, S Xu, Z Dai, L Zhou, T Feng, P Guo, CW Dunn, BR Jones, T Bradley, H Zhu, Y Guan, Y Jiang, G Yu*. treeio: an R package for phylogenetic tree input and output with richly annotated and associated data. Molecular Biology and Evolution. 2020, 37(2):599-603. G Yu*, TTY Lam, H Zhu, Y Guan*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About YuLab</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/about/</guid>
      <description>Research group led by Prof. Guangchuang Yu in School of Basic Medical Sciences, Southern Medical University :smiley:
 __ __ __ __ _____ __ _____ __ \ \/ /_ __/ / ____ _/ /_ / ___// |/ / / / / \ / / / / / / __ `/ __ \______\__ \/ /|_/ / / / / / / /_/ / /___/ /_/ / /_/ /_____/__/ / / / / /_/ / /_/\__,_/_____/\__,_/_.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: guangchuangyu AT gmail.com
Address: 广州市沙太南路1023号南方医科大学生命科学楼10楼生物信息学系
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documents</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/documents/</guid>
      <description>Books  Yu G. Biomedical Knowledge Mining using GOSemSim and clusterProfiler Yu G. Data Integration, Manipulation and Visualization of Phylogenetic Trees Yu G. Gene Ontology Semantic Similarity Analysis Using GOSemSim. In: Kidder B. (eds) Stem Cell Transcriptional Networks. Methods in Molecular Biology, 2020, 2117:207-215. Humana, New York, NY. 余光创, &amp;ldquo;生物信息学II&amp;rdquo;, 《功能蛋白质研究》, 385-425, 何庆瑜 (主编), 科学出版社, 2012. (&amp;ldquo;十二五&amp;quot;国家重点图书出版规划项目)   Workshops  Microbiome dataset analysis using MicrobiotaProcess (BiocAsia 2020) Pathway Analysis (invited workshop for PhD course, University of Southern Denmark)   Supplemental Files  ggtree protocols &amp;ndash; Supplemental file of Current Protocols in Bioinformatics, 2020 Plotting tree with data &amp;ndash; Supplemental file of Molecular Biology and Evolution, 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First snippet</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/snippets/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/snippets/first/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/first/index.md
pwd </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/members/</guid>
      <description>Guangchuang Yu, Phd.
Professor, PI &amp; Associate Director
Department of Bioinformatics, School of Basic Medical Sciences, Southern Medical University
          Zehan Dai, Phd.
Post-doctoral fellow
   Shuangbin Xu
PhD Student
    Tianzhi Wu
PhD Student
   Erqiang Hu
PhD Student
     Lang Zhou
Master&#39;s Student
   Tingze Feng</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/projects/</guid>
      <description>Nothing to see here&amp;hellip; Move along!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/publications/</guid>
      <description>You can visit Google Scholar for details.
# Co-first authors; * Co-corresponding authors
 2021  S Liu, G Yu*, L Liu*, X Zou, L Zhou, E Hu, Y Song. Identification of prognostic Stromal-Immune Score-Based Genes in Hepatocellular Carcinoma microenvironment. Frontiers in Genetics. 2021, 12: 625236.   2020  J He#, S Xu#, B Zhang, C Xiao, Z Chen, F Si, J Fu, X Lin, G Zheng*, G Yu*, J Chen*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second snippet</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/snippets/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/snippets/second/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/second/index.md
ls -la </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>http://yulab-smu.top/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://yulab-smu.top/software/</guid>
      <description> ChIP-seq  ChIPseeker: ChIP peak Annotation, Comparison, and Visualization   Infectious disease and Epidemiology  nCov2019: An R package for exploring COVID-19 statistics seqcombo: Visualization Tool for Sequence Recombination and Reassortment   Knowledge mining  clusterProfiler: Statistical analysis and visualization of functional profiles for genes and gene clusters DOSE: Disease Ontology Semantic and Enrichment analysis enrichplot: Visualization of Functional Enrichment Result GOSemSim: GO-terms Semantic Similarity Measures meshes: MeSH Enrichment and Semantic analyses ReactomePA: Reactome Pathway Analysis   Microbiome  MicrobiotaProcess: Analysis, visualization and biomarker discovery of microbiome   Phylogeny  ggmsa: Plot mutiple sequence alignment using &amp;lsquo;ggplot2&amp;rsquo; ggtree: Visualization of tree and annotation data ggtreeExtra: Phylogenetic tree data annotation seqmagick: Sequence Manipulation Utilities tidytree: A Tidy Tool for Phylogenetic Tree Data Manipulation treeio: Base Classes and Functions for Phylogenetic Tree Input and Output   Visualization  aplot: Decorating a plot with associated information plotbb: Grammar of Graphics for base plot  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
